International Union of Electronic, Electrical, Technical, Salaried and Machine Workers, Local 379, Matchworkers' Union; Records apap024
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
International Union of Electronic Electrical Technical Salaried And Machine Workers Local 379 Match Workers' Union Records
1944-1985
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
International Union Of Electronic Electrical Technical Salaried And Machine Workers Local 379 Match Workers' Union
apap024
1 cubic ft. processed to date
The International Union of Electronic, Electrical, Technical, Salaried, and Machine workers document the day-to-day operations of the first 41 years of this community organization founded in 1944.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted with the exception of one folder, which is marked.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by IUE Local 379, Match Workers on March 6, 1990.
Administrative History
The match workers at the Universal Match plant in Hudson, New York were first organized in 1946 as Federal Labor Union No. 24122. Federal Labor Unions were unions chartered and administered directly by the AFL (and afterwards the AFL-CIO) in trades that otherwise would not have been organized. In 1971 the local voted to affiliate with IUE over the Textile Workers Union of America (whose organizing drive was run by the Hudson Valley Area Joint Board) and became IUE Local 379. In 1981 Swedish Match bought Universal Match Corporation, and by 1989 the firm had closed its Hudson plant, marking the end of Local 379.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains minutes, 1946-1987; state contracts, 1946-1987; state by-laws, 1962-1982; and sample constitutions and contracts from other match workers' unions, 1947-1965.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized alphabetically. There are no series.
Labor; Electronic, Electrical, Technical, Salaried, and Machine Union; International Union; New York (State)--Social conditions; Constitution; Contracts; Administrative records; Minutes; International Union Of Electronic, Electrical,Technical, Salaried And Machine Workers Local 379, Match Workers' Union Records; New York State Local Workers Union
- "AFL-CIO Manual for Shop Stewards,", 1971 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 1)
- Constitution and By-laws, 1962; 1976; 1982 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 2)
- Constitution of American Federation of Labor, 1944 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 3)
- Constitution of AFL-CIO, 1969 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 4)
- Constitution of International Union of Electronic, Electrical, Technical, Salaried & Machine Workers, 1985 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 5)
- Constitutions and By-laws, Samples from Other Unions, 1947; 1956; 1965 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 6)
- Contracts, 1946-1956 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 7)
- Contracts, 1958-1965 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 8)
- Contracts, 1967-1971 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 9)
- Contracts, 1971-1980 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 10)
- Contracts, 1980-1987 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 11)
- Contract Samples from Other Match Workers Locals, 1947-1951 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 12)
- Contract Samples from Other Match Workers Locals, 1955-1961 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 13)
- Contract Samples from Other Unions, 1946, 1948, 1956, 1975 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 14)
- Minutes, 1946-1949 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 15)
- Minutes, 1949-1951 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 16)
- Minutes, 1952-1964 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 17)
- Minutes, 1964-1975 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 18)
- Occupational Safety and Health Pamphlets, 1975 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 19)
- Universal Match Corporation Medical Benefits, 1977-1978; 1983 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 20)
- Universal Match Corporation Retirement Plan, 1982 (Box 1 (International Union of Electronic Electrical Techn), Folder 21)